Guide to the Deane Keller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings, 1936-1978; Series V
  - "The Professional as Art Critic", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Professional Education in a University Community", 1949 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Public schools, 1964 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Retirement, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - "Science and Art", undated (Box 51, Folder 23)
  - "Stamp Design", 1964 (Box 51, Folder 24)
  - "Traditional v. Abstract", 1959 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - "What opportunities have the people of New Haven to see and learn about architecture, painting and sculpture?", 1936 (Box 51, Folder 26)
  - "Yale School of Fine Arts", undated (Box 51, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960, undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
- Teaching, 1930-1968; Series VI
  Teaching is comprised of materials for specific courses, arranged alphabetically by course title, and various lecture notes, arranged chronologically. "Education for War and Reconstruction" was a program held at Yale University during 1942-1943 for enlisted men departing for World War II. Materials from Keller's course on Italian culture include copious lecture notes and assigned reading material. The "Summer Life Drawing and Painting Class" was a beginner's art class open to individuals from New Haven and surrounding communities. Materials include correspondence, syllabi, and class rolls. Lecture notes, which are not associated with specific courses, deal primarily with art history and painting techniques, presumably connected with Keller's teaching at the Yale School of Art.
  - Courses
    - "Education for War and Reconstruction"
      - Lectures, 1942-1943 (Box 52, Folder 1 - 4)
      - Reading material ["American Impressions of Italians and Italian Customs"], 1943 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - "Summer Life Drawing and Painting Class", 1961-1965, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes, 1930-1968, undated (Box 52, Folder 7 - 9)
- Oversize
  - Personal
    - Awards and citations (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Photographs-Deane Keller (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - World War II-Manuscripts Fine Arts and Archives-"Civil Affairs Handbook, Italy, Section 17: Supplement on Cultural Institutions" (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Professional-Artworks
    - Sketches (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Watercolors (Box 53, Folder 5)